Guide to the Melvin Wittler Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Melvin Wittler Papers
1826-2002
1956-1993
RG 201
Yale University Divinity School Library
9
(21 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, and collected material document the life and work of Melvin Wittler, who was an American Protestant missionary in Turkey from 1956 to 1993, and provide insight into religious and political events in the Middle East. Wittler served as an administrator for the Near East Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions and the United Church Board for World Ministries, overseeing the Mission's educational and medical work.
Wittler, Melvin Armin
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Nancy Wittler, 2004.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Arrangement
I. Documentation of Near East Mission, 1830-2002
II. Correspondence, 1952-1995
III. Writings, 1950-1995
IV. Subject Files, 1826-2001
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1949-1996
Biographical / Historical
Melvin Armin Wittler was born on March 25, 1929 in Hartington, Nebraska to Frank William Wittler and Cecil Maria Fiscus. After graduating from Hartington High School in Nebraska in 1947, he received a B.A. from Yankton College, South Dakota in 1951 and a B.Th. from Yankton College School of Theology in 1952. He served as minister at West Point, Nebraska Congregational Church from 1950 to 1952. On August 8, 1953 he married Nancy Patriquin; the Wittlers had three sons and one daughter: Nathan Scott (b. 1957), Bryan Kevin (b. 1961), Heather Ellen (b. 1962) and Bradford Kent (b. 1963). In 1956 Wittler received a B.D. from Hartford Seminary and April 29th of the same year was appointed as a missionary to the Near East Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, which was later known as the United Church Board for World Ministries.. From1957 to1961 Wittler served as teacher of philosophy, American Academy for Girls, Uskudar, Istanbul. In 1960 he became Field Secretary, Near East Mission of United Church Board for World Ministries. He served on the Board of Managers for both the Admiral Bristol Hospital and the Gaziantep American Hospital as well as the American Board Schools. Rev. Wittler also held membership to the Turkish-American University Association, the American Friends of the Middle East, and the Health and Education Foundation. He was active in providing assistance to refugees throughout the region. During a furlough period in 1962 Wittler did graduate study in Oriental Studies at Princeton University. The Wittlers were also on furlough in the U.S. for a year beginning in June 1967. On Tuesday, July 24, 1979, the Mission offices in Istanbul were invaded and bombed by an anti-U.S. militant group. Again in 1991, during the Gulf War, the Istanbul office was bombed by anti-U.S. terrorists. In 1993 the Wittlers retired to West Dummerston, Vermont. Melvin received the Education Award from the American Turkish Council in 1995. He died on February 27, 2003.
Scope and Contents
The Melvin Wittler Papers consist of nine linear feet of material divided into five series: I. Documentation of Near East Mission, 1830-2002; II. Correspondence, 1952-1995; III. Writings, 1950-1995; IV. Subject Files, 1826-2001; V. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1949-1996. This collection contains valuable documentation of Protestant missionary work in Turkey as well as documentation of religious and political events in the Middle East during Wittler's years of service.
Series I, Documentation of Near East Mission is divided into two subseries: Organization and Policy Records, and Institutions/Activities. Material in this series documents the work in Turkey of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions and the United Church Board for World Ministries (Amerikan Bord Heyeti). The series includes meeting minutes, reports, memoranda, and mission newsletters, in addition to materials on the history of the mission and the different schools, hospitals, and other groups it supported.
Series II, Correspondence, includes both personal and general correspondence dating from 1952 to 1995, arranged chronologically. Series III is comprised of writings by Wittler, including student papers from his studies at Yankton College, Hartford Seminary, and Princeton University as well as prayers and sermons. The papers are arranged chronologically. The Subject Files of Series IV contain a wide variety of materials collected by Wittler, including regarding human rights, refugees, Armenian genocide, and church relations as well as materials from conferences, seminars, and meetings that he attended. The final Series encompasses Wittler's personal items such as a household account book and a pastoral recordbook as well as his educational awards, certificates, and newspaper articles about him.
Due to the chaotic state in which the papers were received, their current arrangement is not a reflection of Melvin Wittler's organization but rather an order established by library staff in order to facilitate research in the collection.
Missions -- Middle East; Missions -- Turkey; Missionaries; Wittler, Melvin Armin; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions -- Turkey; United Church Board for World Ministries. Near East Mission
- Documentation of Near East Mission, 1830-2002; Series I
  - Organization and Policy Records
    - History of Mission
      - Aintab Station Record Book: bound volume with handwritten notes, 1885-1917 (Box OV1)
      - Early formation, including re. Aintab, Syria, Cilicia Evangelical Union, Elias Riggs, "Sketch of the Work of the American Board in Cappadocia 1852 - 1904 by Wilson A. Farnsworth and Cesarea Station after 1904 by Adelaide Dwight", 1830-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - American Board in Turkey, including autobiographical sketch by Charles Trowbridge Riggs, 1910-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Including "Some Antecedents to the Political and Religious Environment of the Near East Missions"; Script for filmstrip on American Board work in Turkey; sketches re. American Board missionaries in Turkey, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Including, "Manual of the Near East Mission of the United Church Board for World Ministries"; "The Evolution of a Devolutionary Missionary"; "A Brief History and Description of American Board Schools in Turkey", 1968-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Visitors to mission, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Names and addresses, No date (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Namrun and Greylock properties, 1977, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Bombing incidents at Istanbul Near East Mission office, 1979,1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Reports/ Memos. Newsletters
      - Article on Turkish mission by James Dittes; letters/memos from Margaret Blemker, Secretary for Europe and Near East, ABCFM to Near East Mission, reports on visits to various facilities, etc., 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Memoranda re. mission, meetings, policy; reports on visits, including re. Walter Wiley Foundaton, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Memoranda re. mission, meetings, policy; reports on visits, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Memoranda re. mission, meetings, policy, including re. evangelism; pamphlet: "Eco Resources for Action", 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Mission statements, memoranda, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Mission secretary reports, memoranda, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Mission statements, reports on schools and properties, memoranda, no date (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Circular letters from missionaries in Turkey, 1950-1956, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Near East Mission Newsletters, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Near East Mission Newsletters, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Committee Records
      - Annual reports and various committee minutes, 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Annual reports and various committee minutes, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Annual reports and various committee minutes, 1981-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Staff policy group, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Personnel
      - Information for new missionaries, 1953-1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Memoranda re. furlough of missionary, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Including re. mission job descriptions and reassignment of Dr. and Mrs. Shepard to executive position in Istanbul, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Re. securing teachers, students, culture, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Application forms, 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Re. salaries and policy on leaves and grants, 1968-1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Finances
      - Re. budgets, salaries, 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Re. budgets, salaries, 1972-1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Institutions/ Activities
    - Educational
      - General: American education in Turkey, no date (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Uskudar American Academy: grade book, history of school, 1958-1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Uskudar- student papers, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Tarsus American School: history, 1971-1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - TAS: operations, problems, etc., 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - TAS: personnel evaluations, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - TAS: personnel evaluations (some confidential), 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - American Collegiate Inst. Izmir: reports, curriculum, misc., 1972-1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Turkish Language School: requirements, no date (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Education reports, Including all schools, 1964-1978 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Education surveys, evaluations, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - FABSIT: certificate, by- laws, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 41a)
    - Medical
      - Gaziantep Hospital: History, minutes, reports, 1969-1980 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Gaziantep: Personnel problems, 1969 Jun- Nov (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Gaziantep: Personnel problems, 1969 Dec-1970 Jan (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Admiral Bristol Hospital- Istanbul: Re. property, school of nursing, 1966-1993 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Admiral Bristol Hospital: Re. fundraising, also "Unforgettable Miss Carp", 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Redhouse Press
      - History: Turkish English Dictionary: publishing, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Other Activities
      - Work camp in Turkey, Planned Parenthood, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 1952-1995; Series II
  - Family
    - Letters to/ from family, 1967-1993 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - General
    - Re. MW's ordination, interest in overseas ministry, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Application to ABCFM and appointment to Turkey, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Work in Istanbul, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Wittler's return to Turkey: Re. Uppsala Assembly, Re. change of name of ABCFM to UCBWM, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Including re. Islamic Conference in Jerusalem 7/65, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Including plans for phone call with Plymouth Congregational Church on the occasion of their centennial, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Plans for furlough, death of Nancy's mother, 1967 Jan-May (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Including re. donation of Azariah Smith Hosp. to UCBWM, re. refugees Lebanon/ Israeli war, 1967 Jun-Dec (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Wittler's return to Turkey: re. Uppsala Assembly, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Including position paper of Am. Comm. for Justice in M.E., Tucker request return to Izmir, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Including re. Journal of Ecumenical Studies: relationships with Salem OR church, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Including re. Board Mission relationships: transfer of Wingate Property, remuneration for missionary wives, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Re. Finances and administration: many letters "confidential", 1972 Jan-Jun (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Including re. Hal Schoup denied residence permit and deportation: Christian/ Muslim dialogue, 1972 Jul-Dec (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Including more about Schoup's: Personnel problems at schools, 1973 Jan-Apr. (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Including re. administration and personnel, 1973 May-Dec (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Many about personnel problems at Tarsus: may confidential, 1974 Jan-Jun. (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Including references to Cyprus- Turkey war, Wittler's furlough, 1974 Jul-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Including re. staffing and funding Gaziantep Hospital, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Including re. Turkish crafts, acquisitions, displays, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Including re. personnel and finances of mission schools, 1977 Jan-May (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Including re. personnel and finances of mission schools, 1977 Jun-Oct (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Personal letters re. hospitality: Paper on Jew/ Christian/ Muslim Forum, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Including re. danger from terrorist attacks: Kidnaping of Lloyd Van Vactor (Philippines), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Including re. retirement of M. Blemket, Wittler furlough, 1980 Jan-Jun (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Including re transfer of Gaziantep Hosp. to Mid. East Tech. College, 1980 Jul-Dec (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Including re. imprisonment of Armenian pastor, XXCC delegation to Turkey re. humanitarian work, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Inc. re. missionary compensation, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Letters from friends and visitors, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Wittler's on furlough, Including letter from South Oregon State College re. possible faculty exchange, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - MW visits Soviet Union, letter re. banning distribution of scriptures in Turkey, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Including info. re. John Miskoff Foundation for American students, re. death of Dr. Aharonian, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Including info. re. founding of Robert College, Grievance letter from WA Robeson re. dismissal- TAC, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Letters from friends and visitors, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Letter re. direction of Redhouse Press: note from Ahmet Yesil, brochure of his art, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Info re. bombing of Wittler's office: extending their term, Kurdish refugees, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Including letter re. retirement plans: re. Jinishian Memorial program, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Including letters from people searching info about relatives, school, etc., 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Including re. MW receiving education award, re. David and Virginia Crittenden, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Including re. update on Union Church in Istanbul: undated letters (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Letters in Turkish Language, 1966-1974 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Letters in Turkish Language, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Letters in Turkish Language, 1981-1993 (Box 7, Folder 92)
- Writings, 1950-1995; Series III
  - Essays
    - While at Yankton College
      - B-H, including "Be ye Perfect," "The Church and Drama," "The Holiness of God", circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - N-S, including "The Philosophy of Love," "A Statement of My Personal Christian Faith", circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - While at Hartford Seminary
      - Including "The Holiness of God," "Christology", 1955 (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - Exegesis of I Cor.15, "Assessing the Ideals and Tasks of Turkish Nationalism", 1956 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - While in Turkey
      - Including, "Why a Christian Mission," "Life of the Church in Turkey", 1950s-1980s (Box 7, Folder 97)
    - Later Writings
      - American education in Turkey since 1863, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Sermons
    - A-C, including "Ancient Churches," "Alive and Well," "Ben Gercek" (Turkish), "Buyuk Intigaclaremez" (Turkish), "Consider the Lilies" (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - D-F, including "An Eternal Contemporary," "Foundation and Vision," "The Fullness of Time" (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - G-I, including "The Heart of the Gospel," "I Believe," "Is Christianity a Man's Religion?" (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - L-O, includling "Lest We Forget," "Living on the Horizon," "New Life in the Old," "Our Lord Enters Life" (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - P-S, including "Peace is Personal," "Sevincli Istek" (Turkish), "Shattering Walls of Separation" (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - T-W, including "Thanksgiving," "Where Are You Going?," "The Worth of Beauty" (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Sermon Notes
    - A-C, including "Approve What is Excellent," "Christian Challenge," "The Church at Prayer" (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - D-G, including "The Dependability of God," "Education in Religion," "Family life Importance" (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - H-O, including "The Indigenous Faith," "Into the World," "Open Doors" (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - P-S, including "Power of the Church," "The Sacrament of Living," "Spiritual Lumination" (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - T-Y, including "Teach Religion Make Men Free," "What Makes the Bible Great," "Why a Concern for Christian Mission" (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Misc. sermon notes: untitled (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Sermons by others
    - Including by Harold Bosley, Robert McCracken, and others (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Prayers
    - Including one delivered at dedication at Aleppo, College for Girls (Turkey), Prayers in Turkish language (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Prayers by others
    - John Baillie, E. Campbell, others (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Notebooks
    - Yankton College: class notes, circa 1950 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Yankton College: class notes, circa 1950 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - While pastor in Nebraska, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Hartford Seminary, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Hartford Seminary, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Princeton Seminary, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Writings by others
    - A-C, including Bishop, Blakney, Carleton (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - D-H, including Ditmanson, Guvenc, Habih (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - I-W, including Isely, Nilson, Stowe (Box 10, Folder 122)
- Subject File, 1826-2001; Series IV
  - Social and Political Issues
    - Armenian genocide, 1919-1978 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Armenian genocide, 1982 Aug- 1983 Jul (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Armenian genocide, 1983 Aug- 1984 Dec (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Armenian genocide, including bibliography, 1989 Jul- 2001 Sep (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Ataturk, 1956-1974 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Culture and art: including some plays, 1944-1985 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Cyprus, 1970-1991 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Cyprus, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Economic issues, 1979-1992 (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - Education in Turkey, 1924-1989 (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - Environment, no date (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Human rights: including "Human Rights Review,""Christian minorities in Turkey", 1965 Jul- 1982 Jun (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - Human rights, including publications: "Denying human rights", "Ethnic identity", "The Greeks in Turkey", 1978 Jan- 1992 Mar (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - Iraqi Kurdish refugees, 1987 Jul- 1992 Sep (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - Iraqi Kurdish refugees: Minorities in the Middle East, 1992-1999 (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - Refugee assistance: Individuals, 1982-1989 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Refugees: general: Middle East, 1956-1981 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Job assistance: for 2 individuals, 1983-1991 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Political history of Turkey, 1059-1958 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Political history of Turkey, 1964-1992 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - Wittler's notes on Turkish Government, 1937-1962 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - Wittler's notes: Modern Turkish chronology, no date (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - Politics of Poppy, 1970-1975 (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - Turkish- American relations: Wittler research notes, 1965 Dec- 1976 May (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - Social customs: Women's rights, marriage and divorce, no date (Box 13, Folder 147)
    - Landmines: Jody Williams- coord., no date (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - Landmines: UNICEF collection, no date (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Religion in Turkey
    - General
      - Including dissertation, "Religion and Political Development in Turkey", 1955 Sep- 1976 (Box 13, Folder 150)
    - Christianity
      - General, 1971 Feb- 1981 Apr (Box 13, Folder 151)
      - Church statistics, 1967 May, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 152)
      - Educational facilities, no date (Box 13, Folder 153)
      - Ecumenism, 1967 Jun- 1962 Nov (Box 13, Folder 154)
      - Christian minorities, 1978 Oct- 1987 Oct (Box 13, Folder 155)
      - Christianity: Research notes on early missionaries to Turkey, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 156)
      - Catholic Church: Including copy of pub. "L'Eglise Chaldecne Catholique", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 157)
      - Eastern Orthodox Church: Patriarch Athenagoras I, 1964 Jan- 1972 Jul (Box 14, Folder 158)
      - Eastern Orthodox Church: Patriarch Dimitrios, 1981 Jun- 1991 Oct (Box 14, Folder 159)
      - Eastern Orthodox Church: Patriarch Bartholomew, 1991 Nov 1997 Oct (Box 14, Folder 160)
      - Armenian Orthodox Church, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 161)
      - Syrian Orthodox Church, no date (Box 14, Folder 162)
      - Greek Orthodox Church in USA, 1967 Sep- 1996 Sep (Box 14, Folder 163)
      - Orthodox Churches: General, 1967 Nov- 1991 Nov (Box 14, Folder 164)
    - Dervish Orders
      - Bektasi: News articles in Turkish, no date (Box 14, Folder 165)
      - Mevlevi order (Mevelana), including biography of Mevelana and some of his poetry, no date (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - Islam
      - General info, no date (Box 14, Folder 167)
      - Islam and Christianity, no date (Box 14, Folder 168)
      - Contemporary Islam: includes some study series, no date (Box 14, Folder 169)
      - Wittler's research notes re. Islam, no date (Box 14, Folder 170)
  - Organizations and Conferences
    - American Friends of the M.E., 1967-1991 (Box 15, Folder 171)
    - American-Turkish Friendship Council, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 172)
    - Americans for Middle East Understanding, 1970 Mar-Apr (Box 15, Folder 173)
    - Center for Middle East Studies: Newsletter, 1990 Spring (Box 15, Folder 174)
    - Christian Mission to Islam, no date (Box 15, Folder 175)
    - Churches for Middle East Peace, no date (Box 15, Folder 176)
    - Contemporary Turkish Thought, 1962 Oct- 1963 Mar (Box 15, Folder 177)
    - Current Turkish Thought: Newsletter, 1969 Nov- 1974 Dec (Box 15, Folder 178)
    - Development Foundation of Turkey, 1982-1992 (Box 15, Folder 179)
    - The Edward F. Gallahue Conference on World Religions, 1966 May (Box 15, Folder 180)
    - Lutheran World Federation, 1964 Aug (Box 15, Folder 181)
    - Middle East Council of Churches: including Consultation on Dialogue and Witness 2/1975, 1972-1975 (Box 15, Folder 182)
    - MECC: including consultation on Christian Presence and Witness 10/1980, 1975-1981 (Box 15, Folder 183)
    - MECC: including dossier and Christians for Peace in the Holy Land, 1989 Nov (Box 15, Folder 184)
    - MECC: Reports and notes (Box 15, Folder 185)
    - Middle East Institute: Newsletter, 1958 Oct (Box 15, Folder 186)
    - Middle East Studies Assoc.: Annual meeting programs, 1992 Aug- 1993 Nov (Box 15, Folder 187)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1955-1992 (Box 15, Folder 188)
    - Missionary Research Library: occassional bulletins, 1964 Dec- 1967 Feb (Box 15, Folder 189)
    - Missionary Research Library: occassional bulletins, 1968 Jun- 1969 Apr (Box 16, Folder 190)
    - Missionary Research Library: occassional bulletins, 1969 Jul- 1970 Feb (Box 16, Folder 191)
    - Missionary Research Library: occassional bulletins, 1970 Mar- 1972 Mar (Box 16, Folder 192)
    - Muslims of America: Includes information on American Islamic College, 1988 Apr (Box 16, Folder 193)
    - National Council of Churches of Christ: Includes papers on mission of the church, evangelism, corporate interests, 1955, 1966 Mar, 1973 Feb (Box 16, Folder 194)
    - NCCC: Includes Middle East policy statement and proposed project in economic development of Greece, 1980 Nov (Box 16, Folder 195)